Saif Kbishi

0526901487 | saifkbishi@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github

Summary:

FullStack Web Developer with experience in **JavaScript**, **React**, **NodeJs** and many other technologies. As a former Technical Support Engineer with **BS.c. in Software Engineering** - I'm driven to project my skills in **solving problems** into the software world.

Education:

2021: Full Stack JavaScript Bootcamp graduate - Appleseeds Academy.

Intensive 6-months, 720 hours training program that encourages self-led learning as well as group projects that simulate real-world development teams.

Learning and applying MERN stack. (MongoDB, Express, ReactJs, NodeJs).

2013: B.Sc in Software engineering, Ort Braude Karmiel.

2011: CCNA Network Management course graduate - CISCO.

2011: QA graduate - Qualitest: ISTQB, networks, STR, STD, STP.

Project:

MyBalance - a MERN fullstack (MongoDB, Express, ReactJs, NodeJs) CRUD application.

The back-end **server** uses Node.js + Express for **REST APIs**, the front-end side is a React client with **React Router**, **Axios** & **Bootstrap**. **Bcrypt** for user authentication and file upload, to keep track of daily expenses balance.

College final project on Rapid Face Recognition Using Hashing based on OMP algorithm.

Work Experience:

2021: A group project for Appleseeds (a non-profit association), refactoring management portal from **AngularJS to React**, examining the former portal design, **API** calls & responses testing them in **Postman** and developing better components utilizing **React** library and **Material-UI** framework.

2013 - 2020: Experienced Technical Support Engineer - SeatGeek Inc. Online application mainly. 2011-2013: QA tester at Qualitest- Personal Data Dashboard website, Microsoft project.

Computer skills and technologies:

Programming languages: MERN stack (MongoDb, Express, ReactJs, NodeJs), JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, MySql, JQuery, TypeScript, Jest.

Other technologies: Github, Heroku, JIRA, SalesForce, AWS.

Military Service:

2002-2006 Duty service in the Artillery corps, released as Lieutenant.

Volunteering:

2008-2012: working with youth in "Aharai Lezahal" (אחרי לצה"ל).

<u>Languages:</u>

Arabic - mother tongue; Hebrew - as a mother tongue; English - well proficient.